[
  {
    "id": "a0001",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The range of 2-hour post challenge glucose levels is - Impaired glucose tolerance",
    "correctAnswer": "140 - 199 mg/dl",
    "optionValues": [
      "100 – 199 mg/dl",
      "120 – 199 mg/dl",
      "130 – 199 mg/dl",
      "140 - 199 mg/dl",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0002",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The range of impaired fasting glucose is",
    "correctAnswer": "100 – 125 mg/dl",
    "optionValues": [
      "90 – 100 mg/dl",
      "100 – 125 mg/dl",
      "110 – 125 mg/dl",
      "120 – 125 mg/dl",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0003",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The antibodies which lead to destruction of beta cells is",
    "correctAnswer": "all of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "islet cell autoantibodies",
      "IA2",
      "GAD",
      "all of the above",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0004",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Hepatic glucose production leads to",
    "correctAnswer": "lipotoxicity",
    "optionValues": [
      "lipolysis",
      "lipotoxicity",
      "glucotoxicity",
      "all of the above",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0005",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Congenital or acquired syndromes leads to",
    "correctAnswer": "acanthosisnigricans",
    "optionValues": [
      "fibrocalculuspancreatopathy",
      "protein deficient diabetes",
      "acanthosisnigricans",
      "all of the above",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0006",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Endocrinopathy can coexist with altered functions of",
    "correctAnswer": "all of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "pituitary",
      "adrenal",
      "thyroid",
      "all of the above",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0007",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Normal ranges of oxygen tension (PaCO2) is",
    "correctAnswer": "80 – 100 mm Hg",
    "optionValues": [
      "70 – 100 mm Hg",
      "80 – 100 mm Hg",
      "90 – 100 mm Hg",
      "all of the above",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0008",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Dyspnea is defined as",
    "correctAnswer": "shortness of breath",
    "optionValues": [
      "decreased oxygen levels in the blood circulation",
      "loss of intercoastal muscle mass",
      "shortness of breath",
      "all of the above",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0009",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The organ responsible for long-term control of Blood Pressure is",
    "correctAnswer": "Kidney",
    "optionValues": [
      "Lungs",
      "Liver",
      "Kidney",
      "Heart",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0010",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "In moderate salt restriction the acceptable intake of sodium is",
    "correctAnswer": "1-1.5g",
    "optionValues": [
      "2-3 g",
      "1-1.5g",
      "500-700 mg",
      "200-300 mg",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0011",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Systolic blood pressure in prehypertensive condition is",
    "correctAnswer": "120-139 mmHg",
    "optionValues": [
      "≥160 mmHg",
      "140-159 mmHg",
      "<120 mmHg",
      "120-139 mmHg",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0012",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "For hypercholesterolemic patients, dietary intake of cholesterol should be restricted to less than",
    "correctAnswer": "200 mg/d",
    "optionValues": [
      "200 mg/d",
      "250 mg/d",
      "300 mg/d",
      "350 mg/d",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0013",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "One of the risk factors for CVD is HDL level less than",
    "correctAnswer": "40 mg/dL",
    "optionValues": [
      "55 mg/dL",
      "45 mg/dL",
      "50 mg/dL",
      "40 mg/dL",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0014",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Products labeled as ‘sodium free’ should have sodium content",
    "correctAnswer": "<5 mg",
    "optionValues": [
      "0 mg",
      "<5 mg",
      "35 mg",
      "140 mg",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0015",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The instrument used to measure blood pressure is known as",
    "correctAnswer": "Sphygmomanometer",
    "optionValues": [
      "Barometer",
      "Glucometer",
      "Infantometer",
      "Sphygmomanometer",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0016",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Normal serum triglyceride level is",
    "correctAnswer": "<150 mg/dL",
    "optionValues": [
      "<150 mg/dL",
      "150-199 mg/dL",
      "200-499 mg/dL",
      "≥500 mg/dL",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0017",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Optimum serum LDL cholesterol level is",
    "correctAnswer": "<100 mg/dL",
    "optionValues": [
      "<150 mg/dL",
      "<120 mg/dL",
      "<100 mg/dL",
      "<160 mg/dL",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0018",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Another name for Decompensated Heart Disease is",
    "correctAnswer": "Myocardial Infarction",
    "optionValues": [
      "Myocardial Infarction",
      "Angina Pectoris",
      "Atherosclerosis",
      "Ischemia",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0019",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Risk factors for which intervention have proven to lower the CVD risk come under",
    "correctAnswer": "Category 1",
    "optionValues": [
      "Category 4",
      "Category 3",
      "Category 2",
      "Category 1",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0020",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The phytochemicals present in soyabean and its products are:",
    "correctAnswer": "Isoflavones",
    "optionValues": [
      "Anthocyanins",
      "Isoflavones",
      "Carotenoids",
      "Sulfides",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0021",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Trachea is part of upper respiratory tract",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0022",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Iron is a surfactant",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0023",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Fat oxidation as a main energy source is preferred in COPD",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0024",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Pathological changes in the small airways lead to Chronic Bronchitis",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0025",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Acetoacetic acid leads to fruity odour of the breath",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0026",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Sugar reading of > 200 mg/dl is indicative of risk to ketosis",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0027",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Hyperventilation is one of the symptoms of ketoacidosic coma",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0028",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "HDL-cholesterol helps in the process of Reverse Cholesterol Transport",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0029",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Step II TLC diet allows for the cholesterol intake upto300 mg/d",
    "correctAnswer": "False",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0030",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "In TLC diet, saturated fat should provide <7 % of the total calories",
    "correctAnswer": "True",
    "optionValues": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ]
  }
]